## SERGIO RUIZ

# FULLSTACK JAVASCRIPT DEVELOPER

serginator@gmail.com http://www.serginator.com

FullStack JavaScript developer with 5+ years industry experience, since age of 6 with computers and since age of 12 dealing with code, with strong skills in code quality, performance and continuous integration. I have the capacity to learn new languages and adaptability to new environments in no time thanks to my overall knowledge of languages and operative systems.

## SKILLS

WEB DEVELOPMENT

HTML5 CSS3 JAVASCRIPT REST AJAX BOOTSTRAP NODE.JS

JAVASCRIPT JQUERY ANGULARJS NODE.JS ZEPTO.JS UNDERSCORE

CONTINUOUS JENKINS SONAR GRUNT.JS UNIX

INTEGRATION

DATABASES MYSQL SQLITE NOSQL MONGODB

SCM GIT GITHUB SVN TFS

## **EMPLOYMENT**

Systems Integration Consultant - Junior Programmer , CIBER Junior Programmer at System Integration developing a social network. HTML CSS JavaScript AJAX PHP ELGG MySQL Unix

2011-06 — 2011-12

Systems Integration Consultant - Programmer, CIBER

2012-01 — 2012-12

Programmer at System Integration, I've been developing a social network, Android apps, rest services at BBVA GAE project, sites with Google Sites for internal documentation at BBVA and Telepizza's mobile app. HTML HTML5 CSS CSS3 JavaScript PHP ELGG Android GAE Java Google Sites C# ASP.NET MVC 4 Zepto.js jQuery AJAX JSON REST Apache nginx

Analyst Programmer, AURIGAE

2011-12 — Present

Software Developer at Telefónica I+D

HTML5 CSS3 JavaScript Unix AngularJS Mocha Sinon Chai LESS Git Github Scrum JIRA Jenkins Grunt.js Jasmine Google Cast SDK SVN jQuery SVG Sonar AJAX Node.js APS POA PBA Clean Code

## PROJECTS

Creator, JS Test Lab An arcade machine JavaScript HTML5 CSS3 2011-03 — Present

#### Contributor, DTH Hybrid - Movistar TV

2015-01 — Present

Development of the UI using SVG and JavaScript to communicate with the middleware. Also I've installed and configured all the continuous integration environment with Jenkins and Sonar, and made the Grunt.js tasks to automate everything, from linting or testing to opening pull requests automagically with new translations from the OBs.

JavaScript jQuery jasmine AJAX SVG Unix Jenkins Sonar Scrum JIRA SVN Git Github video straming hd drm opentv

#### Contributor, Movistar TV GO

2015-02 — 2015-03

Joined the team for one month to speed development of new features.

JavaScript AngularJS Mocha Sinon Chai HTML5 CSS3 LESS AJAX Git Github Scrum JIRA Jenkins Grunt.js

#### Contributor, Chromecast Receiver for Movistar TV GO

2015-01 — Present

Developed the Chromecast Receiver for Movistar TV in Angular JS. Also installed and configured all the continuous integration environment with Jenkins and Sonar, and made the Grunt.js tasks to automate everything, from linting or testing to opening pull requests automagically with new translations from the OBs.

JavaScript AngularJS Jasmine HTML5 CSS3 Google Cast SDK AJAX Jenkins Sonar Grunt.js video streaming hd drm

#### Contributor, DTH Hybrid - Movistar TV

2012-12 — 2013-12

Development of the UI using SVG and JavaScript to communicate with the middleware. Also I've installed and configured all the continuous integration environment with Jenkins and Sonar, and made the Grunt.js tasks to automate everything, from linting or testing to opening pull requests automagically with new translations from the OBs.

JavaScript jQuery jasmine AJAX SVG Unix Jenkins Sonar Scrum JIRA SVN Git Github video straming hd drm opentv

#### Contributor, CSB - Cloud Service Broker

2014-01 — 2014-11

Development of an APS 1.2 to integrate McAfee Multi Access in CSB, front-end (in Dojo Toolkit) and backend (in Node.js), for O2 (UK and GER) and VIVO (Brazil). Also made all the ci environment.

JavaScript HTML CSS Node.js Mocha Sinon Chai AJAX APS 1.2 POA PBA Scrum JIRA Git Github Unix Jenkins Grunt.js

#### Contributor, Telepizza - Mobile app development

2012-09 — 2012-12

Development of the Smartphone/Tablet application, with our own javascript framework to load all sections dynamically in a single page application.

C# ASP.NET MVC 4 HTML5 CSS3 JavaScript Zepto.js ¡Query AJAX TFS

#### Contributor, BBVA - Google App Engine (GAE) Team

2012-06 — 2012-09

Development of services and apps for BBVA using Google App Engine (GAE). After the development of several REST services, I created some documentation webs for internal projects using Google Sites and developing gadgets in Google Apps Script.

Java Google App Engine REST JavaScript JSON Google Sites Google Apps Script PSD to HTML5/4 and CSS3/2

#### Contributor, Android app for HEEL

2012-02 — 2012-02

Development of a tablet app (Android) for a pharmaceutical laboratory. This app is used to let pharmacists to fill and sign contracts of sale and purchase, with a pharmacy database. It captures the form as a digital image and stores the filled form in CVS format to post-process it.

Java Android SDK SQLite

#### Contributor, Development of a Social Network

2011-06 — 2012-06

Social network development using ELGG and modifying it's core. It was running for two or three years, being announced in several media around the country.

PHP ELGG JavaScript JSON AJAX JQuery MySQL HTML CSS Unix LAMP SVN Photoshop CS5 PSD to

## **EDUCATION**

Engineering in Computer Science, Universidad Complutense de

2005-10 — 2010-12

Madrid - UCM

Studied Engineering in Computer Science until 3rd grade, passed all programming labs.

Software development for Android devices, Universidad Nacional de

2011-01 — 2012-01

Educación a Distancia - UNED

Android development

Android UX Programming Design

Dreamweaver CS4, Universidad Complutense de Madrid - UCM

2010-01 — 2010-01

Course certified by UCM about HTML4, CSS2 and Dreamweaver.

An Introduction to Interactive Programming in Python, Rice University

2013-01 — 2013-01

A course by Rice University at Coursera, Graded with distinction:

https://www.coursera.org/records/XKhb4VhWeYRPvHnc

game development python

Web development with Angular JS, Imagina Formación

2015-12 — 2016-02

Angular JS course

angularjs javascript html5 css3 animations

### **AFFILIATION**

Member, Grupo de Estudio de JavaScript

2011-08 — 2011-09

Study group formed by several members of the JavaScript community in Madrid to learn and debate about JavaScript ecosystem.

Co-Organizer and member, MadridJS Meetup

2011-08 — Present

Co-Organizer of MadridJS, helping with talks and organization but with the lack of time, just member since 2015

*Member*, HTML5 Spain Meetup Member of HTML5 Spain

2012-02 — Present

### SPEAKING

Game development in JavaScript, MadridJS Meetup

2012

It was a conference Carlos and I did about Game Development in JavaScript. It was in CAMON, with around 90 attendees. Here is the video, slides and info about the session.

Workshop: Game programming in JavaScript, GameMe5

2013

Advanced workshop on how to develop a game without libraries, plain JavaScript, for the GameMe5 event. In this workshop we showed and explained in four hours, step by step, a shootem up demo. The game can be played here and the repo with more info can be watched here.